tivo.com 2016-10-14

# Privacy Policy | TiVo

Effective as of September 26, 2016

Our goal is to give TiVo users and customers the best TV-watching experience possible, and we have updated this policy so that TiVo users and customers can better understand our treatment of their personal information.

## Introduction

This privacy policy describes how TiVo collects, uses, discloses, and protects information received from or about users of our products and services.

 _A few things to note:_

  * When we refer to “TiVo products” in this policy, we mean any device, software, or website offered by any TiVo company or subsidiary (including TiVo DVRs, the TiVo Mini, the TiVo Stream, TiVo mobile apps, and tivo.com).
  * When we say “you” in this policy, we mean both you and any other individuals you let use your TiVo device, software, or account.
  * When we say “we”, “us” or “our” in this policy, we mean TiVo, and/or one or more of its corporate affiliates. TiVo Corporation is incorporated in the State of Delaware and its principle office is 2 Circle Star Way, San Carlos CA 94070 USA.  This policy covers TiVo Corporation, and its subsidiaries, which includes Rovi Corporation and its subsidiaries, and TiVo Inc. and its subsidiaries.
  * TiVo products provided to you directly by your cable or satellite provider are subject to their privacy policy (and not this policy).

This policy may be amended from time to time without notice and it is your responsibility to read it carefully and review any changes that may have been made. Since changes will be posted on this page, we encourage you to check this page regularly.

This policy, the processing of your online account data and any other data we collect shall be governed by the laws of the State of California and shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in San Mateo County, California.

## Collection and Use of Information

 ** _How do we collect information?_**

We collect information (both automatically and when we ask you to provide it) when you use TiVo products, place orders, contact customer service, and participate in surveys. We may also let you link a TiVo product with your account on a third-party service, such as Facebook or Twitter. We may also acquire a business that has information about you, or otherwise acquire information about you from third parties.

 ** _What information are we collecting?_**

Information we ask you to provide us may include, for example, your name, email address, phone number, shipping address, billing address, credit card information, and age or other demographic information.

Information we automatically collect may include, for example, data about your viewing behavior (such as how you use, watch, record, rate and interact with content accessed on or through TiVo products), device (such as model number, software versions, and unique device identifiers), location (such as GPS data, zip code, and time zone), and cable service (such as cable provider and cable channels). We may also collect information that does not directly identify you and is collected as you use our products and services, including your IP address, and information gathered with the use of a "cookie" (cookies are discussed further below), and information related to searches or recommendations on TiVo’s products and services. Such information collected includes, without limitation, which pages and content are browsed, interactions with advertising and content, and other data related to preferences and usage.

Information we collect from your account on a third-party service with your consent may include data about you and your friends from that service (such as what you or they have liked or shared).

 _\- Anonymous Data_

We may create Anonymous Data records from personal information by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the data personally identifiable to you. Once we create Anonymous Data this Anonymous Data is our property. We use this Anonymous Data in many ways including analyzing request and usage patterns, creating reports and performing analytics so that we may enhance the content of our Services, improve Site navigation and provide meaningful analysis of habits, usage, trends, and effectiveness of marketing campaigns etc. as part of our analytics and other services. Company reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Data to Third-Party Companies in its absolute discretion.

 _\- Social Media and Profiles_

For certain TiVo products and services, the information that we may ask you to provide could include name, gender, location, email address, biographical information and the movies and television shows that you like to watch. When you create your profile, you may be asked if you want your profile to be public or private. Unless you state that you want your profile to be private your profile will be available for public viewing.

 _\- Public Content_

Your photos, posts, friends, and other content you post to the TiVo products and services (and your Profile if you designate it as public, including your first name and last initial but excluding any other account registration information) are meant for public consumption. We may display this content on any of the TiVo products and/or services and further distribute it to a wider audience through third-party sites and services.

 _\- Facebook and other Social Networking Sites_

If you are logged into Facebook or another Social Networking Site (“SNS”) that we support, and you access but are not logged into the TiVo service or product, we may receive information from Facebook or the SNS to make it easier for you to create an account on the TiVo product or service in question and to show our relevant content from your Facebook or SNS friends. This information personalizes your experience and helps you create an account (where this facility is available). You may also be able to connect your account on TiVo’s website to your accounts on Facebook or other SNSs, in which case we may collect and store information identifying your account with the third-party service. We use this information to help you connect and share public content with your friends and followers.

 _\- Material You Choose to Reveal in On-­line Fora, Blogs, Message Boards, Chat Rooms or Similar Locations_

You may be able to post personally information on areas of a TiVo product or service that may be viewed by other users or the public, although we recommend that you do not do so. Please note that there are risks, including but not limited to the risk of physical harm, of dealing with strangers, including persons who may be acting under false pretenses. Please choose carefully the information you post on any of the TiVo products or services and that you give to other TiVo users. You are discouraged from publicly posting your full name, telephone numbers, street addresses or other information that identifies you or allows strangers to find you or steal your identity. Despite this prohibition, other people’s information may be offensive, harmful or inaccurate, and in some cases will be mislabeled or deceptively labeled.

YOU ASSUME ALL RISKS ASSOCIATED WITH DEALING WITH OTHER USERS WITH WHOM YOU COME IN CONTACT THROUGH ROVI PROPERTIES. WE EXPECT THAT YOU WILL USE CAUTION AND COMMON SENSE WHEN USING TIVO’S PRODUCTS AND SERVICES.

 _­_

 _\- Tracking and Cookies_

When you visit TiVo websites, we and our advertising partners may store and access information from your device, including "cookies", clear GIFs (which are also sometimes called web bugs or web beacons) and browser details. We may collect information such as your browser type, the type of operating system you use, the domain name of your Internet service provider, IP address, pages visited on the site, services used and how you have used them. We and our advertising partners do this for a variety of purposes. In the case of our advertising associates, this may include the personalization of advertisements based on your visits to sites in that party’s network.

Please note that at least some of the TiVo websites do not currently respond to a web browser’s “do not track” instructions (e.g., a “do not track” signal). However, we may use Google analytics. Google analytics manages ‘Do Not Track’ instructions from your browser in accordance with its own privacy policies <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. Another example of how we use cookies might be to track the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising campaigns and to show you TiVo ads on other websites after you have visited our website. Please see our cookie policy at https://www.tivo.com/legal/privacy for more information.

We may also work with third-party advertising companies that collect and use information to deliver more relevant advertising across the Internet and when you are using our products and services. To learn more about this practice and your choices with regard to companies participating in industry self-regulation, visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

Please note: if you continue to use this website, or any other TiVo website, we will imply from this that you consent to our use of cookies.

Information about our use of cookies is contained in our Cookie Policy at https://www.tivo.com/legal/cookies

 _\- Email_

Email addresses are used for identification, inviting new friends to Rovi Properties, searching for and finding friends, general communication, order processing and to send notifications to you. To facilitate searching for and finding friends on the Rovi Properties, Rovi allows users to search for other members using text searches, first and last name, email address, and by using other attributes. Users can invite friends to join certain Rovi Properties by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. Where permitted by applicable law, Rovi stores these email addresses so that the respondents may be added to the friend list of the member sending the invitations and to establish relationships between users.

 ** _How do we use information we collect about you?_**

We use the information we collect to provide you with requested products and services, notify you of changes to our policies or products, notify you of offers that may interest you, process your orders, assist you in purchasing TiVo products, activate and renew your subscriptions, identify or troubleshoot issues, conduct surveys, improve the products and services we provide to you, and otherwise operate our business.

As part of providing you with a more personalized experience when using TiVo products, we may use information we collect to:

  * analyze your viewing habits (which lets us do things like suggest a particular TV show or movie that you may enjoy);
  * analyze your usage of TiVo product features (which lets us understand things like how many times a particular TV show was recorded, or how many of our users are watching content on a Netflix or YouTube app);
  * combine information we collect from your use of different TiVo products (which lets us do things like make it possible for you to start a show in one room and finish it in another); and
  * show you more relevant ads (both on TiVo products and on third-party websites).  In particular, we may use your personal information and non-­personal information to serve ads to you via TiVo’s products and services as well as to provide you with promotions, products and services. We may also use third-­party advertising companies and other business associates to serve ads on TiVo’s products and services or other sites and provide you with promotions, products and services. These third-party advertising companies and our business associates may be located throughout the world.

These third-­party advertising companies and business associates may receive and share with us information relating to the advertisements that they serve you including, without limitation, date and time of ad shown, the ad that was shown and your IP address and your interactions with such advertisements. These third­-party advertising companies and business associates may use cookies, clear GIFs and anonymous information about your visits to TiVo’s websites and other websites to measure and improve the effectiveness of their ads, promotions, products and services.

This information may also be used for online preference and other targeted marketing purposes. The information received by these third­-party advertising companies and business associates is subject to the privacy policies of these third-­party advertising companies and business associates. We may be given access to this information by these third-­party advertising companies and business associates which we may use for purposes including, without limitation, to provide services to you, to better target advertising and content to you and to generate statistics and reports and to carry out analytics that help us to provide our services, to create new products and services, to better target advertising and content, (on our and our business associates’ websites, applications and devices) to generate statistics, reports and for various analytic purposes. We may make certain information about you available to third­-party advertising companies and other business associates under agreements between us and those third-­party advertising companies and business associates. The third­-party advertising companies and business associates will use that information to target advertising to you or provide and market promotions, products and services to you. You may withdraw your consent to our sending your personal information to advertising companies and business associates by sending us a written e­mail request from the e­mail address that is registered with us. If you do so we will not provide your personal information from the relevant TiVo product or service to third-party advertisers or business associates from the time you opt out. However where permitted by applicable law, we may still provide them with information that does not directly identify you from which they may send you targeted advertisements.

Many of our advertising associates are part of the Network Advertising Initiative. You may opt-­out of behavioral advertising for Network Advertising Initiative member companies by following the link below and opting-­out of all or some of the advertising networks:

(Opting-out of Flash Cookies is described above in the tracking information section.)

We may also use information we collect in our analytics business, where we use data that has been either de-identified or aggregated (or both) to generate insights into consumer behaviors (for example, to show what the most watched commercial was during a particular show).

If we acquire a business that has information about you, or otherwise acquire information about you from third parties, we may (subject to applicable law) combine that information with the information we already hold. This should enable us to provide you with improved or enhanced products or services.

## Disclosure of Personal Information

As is common across websites, to use certain features of TiVo’s products and services, we may ask you to register, create an account, provide your full name and email address and create a password. Once you have created an account, you will have the option to fill out a form (all or portions of which may be included in your profile). When you create your profile, we collect personal information about you, such as name, address, location, e­mail address, etc. which will be stored in order to provide services to you and to conduct activities including, without limitation, using it to process your registration, maintain a profile about you, process your request to receive newsletters and email announcements, or to voluntarily participate in surveys or contests and/or to communicate with you about services and products we think may be of interest to you.

We are not in the business of selling your personal information to third parties. We will disclose your personal information to third parties only if:

  * we get your consent;
  * we are required to do so by applicable law, legal process, and/or governmental authorities;
  * we believe disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, our customers, or others;
  * we are involved in a merger, acquisition, partial or total sale of assets, or other corporate change;
  * they are a joint venture partner or an entity we own or control (or that owns or controls us) that is either subject to this policy or follows privacy practices at least as protective as these; or
  * they provide services to us (such as processing credit card payments or collecting past due debts) and have agreed to use your information only for the purposes we request.

We may disclose de-identified, aggregated, or other non-personal information to third parties in our discretion. For example, we may provide reports showing aggregated information regarding our users to advertisers, networks, and others (like a report that shows what type of viewers watch a particular TV show, so that advertisers can reach similar viewers on other platforms).

Note that TiVo products may include commenting, forums, sharing, or other similar functionality. Information that you provide using these features (such as your name, your posts, or TV shows you have watched) may be available to other users or the general public.

## Protection of Personal Information

We have reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative measures in place to safeguard the security of your personal information

## Third-Party Services

Our products and services may enable you to access or otherwise use third-party products and services, and our websites may contain links to third-party websites. Such third parties have their own policies that govern their collection, use, and disclosure of information. We suggest that you read their privacy policies to learn about their practices. 

You may choose to link your accounts on certain social networking services with your TiVo account or with your TiVo products (such as a TiVo DVR or mobile app). If you do so, you may be able to publish information to the linked social networking service, and we may be able to publish such information on your behalf. Please note that any information you choose to publish to or share with the linked social networking service (such as your viewing information) will become subject to the privacy policy and other terms of that service.

## Your Choices

Email: If you do not want to receive marketing emails from us, you can change your email preferences by logging into your account on tivo.com or clicking on the included “unsubscribe” link (though you will still receive certain account-related emails). We will send you marketing emails only where we are permitted to do so by applicable law.

Cookies: If you do not want us to store or otherwise use cookies on your computer, your browser may offer tools to disable or reject cookies (though you may not be able to use some website features if you do so). To learn more about your choices with regard to third-party advertising companies participating in industry self-regulation, visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

Mobile apps: If you do not want us to collect location data from a TiVo mobile app, you can disable location services on your mobile device.

TiVo DVRs and the TiVo Mini: If you do not want us to use your viewing logs in our analytics business or share that de-identified information with third parties, you can opt out by logging into your account on tivo.com or calling us at 1-877-367-8486. If you have a TiVo Series 2 or Series 3 DVR and opt out, we will not collect your viewing logs. If you have a TiVo Series 4 or newer TiVo product (such as a TiVo Mini or a TiVo Roamio or Premiere series DVR) and opt out, we will still collect your viewing logs, but will use them only to provide you with features of the TiVo service as described in this policy (for example, to suggest a particular TV show that you may enjoy).

## Accessing and Updating Your Personal Information

You can access, update, and correct or delete inaccuracies in your personal information that we collect and maintain in our regular business records by logging into your account on tivo.com or calling us at 1-877-367-8486. We reserve the right (subject to applicable law) to decline requests that are impractical or may jeopardize the privacy of others.

## Security and Retention Policies

We use commercially reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. However, due to the design of the Internet, ever-­changing technology and other factors outside of our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties or that we will not be subject to security breaches. We will have no liability for disclosure of personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized or unlawful acts of third parties.

You are responsible for the security of your user name, ID and password for any of the TiVo products and services. Please take care when using and storing them.

## Overseas Transfers and the Processing of Your Information

Some of your personal information may be used by us and our affiliates, subsidiaries and our suppliers who may be located in countries outside the country where you are located for the purposes outlined in this policy. The data protection laws in these countries may not offer the same level of protection as those in the country where you are located. By providing your personal information to us you understand and expressly consent to us and our business associates and suppliers processing your data in any jurisdiction, including without limitation the United States of America, in accordance with this privacy policy.

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

TiVo Inc. and its subsidiaries comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Economic Area to the United States.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome) website, privacyshield.gov. To learn more about TiVo Inc.’s participation in the Privacy Shield Framework, please see TiVo’s Inc.’s Privacy Shield Notice.

## Your Rights

 ** _Your California Privacy Rights_**

If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you in this Privacy Policy with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt-­out (or "unsubscribe") of our use and sharing of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third-party disclosure choices, please send a request by email to [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com) or by postal mail to TiVo at 2160 Gold Street, San Jose, CA 95002-2160, Attn: Your California Privacy Rights, c/o Privacy Group, Legal Department. All requests must be labeled "Your California Privacy Rights" in the email subject line or envelope or post card. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights", include your name, street address, city, state, zip code and e­mail address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email) and indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail). We are unable to accept requests via the telephone or by facsimile. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

## Changes to this Policy

We may update this policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new policy online on this page, and if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of privacy policy changes). 

## Questions

If you have any questions about this policy, please send an email to [privacy@tivo.com](mailto:privacy@tivo.com), or send a letter to TiVo Corp, attn: Privacy - Legal Department, 2160 Gold Street, San Jose, CA 95002-2160.
